SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Career Overview

Wide range of experience in the architecture, design and development of software products in the area of management applications, subsystems, and infrastructure in a variety of environments ranging from embedded systems, platform operating systems, SDKs. Proven skills in the areas of object-oriented architecture and design, delivery of high quality industry leading products, and technical and group leadership and management. Qualifications

Languages:;C, C++, Java, Ruby, Perl, Assembly, Shell (various) Operating Systems;Linux, Windows, UNIX, Solaris Technologies:;PMBus, IPMI, SNMP, RPC, COM, CIM, XML, UML, MFC, PTHREADS OO Design, Embedded Systems, Clustering, Kernel/Drivers, Multi-threading

Work Experience

Software Engineer 01/2009 to Current Proquest Baton Rouge, LA

• Development information.

Software Systems Lead 12/2006 to 01/2009 Vera Bradley, Inc. Fairlawn, OH

- Early stage startup developing new generation power converter chip technology.
- I am responsible for driving the architecture and development of SDK, interfaces, and design and management applications.
- In addition I participate in the verification of chip digital interface through the use of cross-platform software developed for Power Management devices.

Team Lead/Architect 09/2001 to 12/2006 Vera Bradley, Inc. Fort Worth, TX

- Embedded Systems Application Architecture/Design/Development I developed innovative management solutions for Newisys scalable system architecture to be used in rack mount and blade server systems.
- This involves work with OEM customers and internal product development teams.
- As one of the first members of the embedded systems management team for Newisys, I led a software team to deliver the entire software stack on an embedded service processor.
- I initially developed much of the object oriented architecture and design of the system management application software for Newisys servers.
- The delivered product included components that handled management of system events, monitoring of instrumented sensors, security model, IPMI enablement, provision for web interface management, SNMP access to management data, trap indications for critical system events, etc.
- During this time I also acted as an author of the ipmitool SourceForge project.
- Acted as software organization liaison between ODMs/OEMs and Newisys to successfully deploy systems within partner requirements.
- Responsibilities included facilitation of deliverables, quality, defect resolution, futures planning, and management of expectations.

Team Lead 01/2001 to 09/2001 LSI Logic City, STATE

Responsible for complete architecture/design of embedded storage controller features; developed functional specifications, UML models
and design specification; managed and led Austin-based development team to deliver Remote Volume Mirroring feature for LSI storage
controller.

Team Lead 04/1998 to 01/2001 Dell Computer City, STATE

- Responsible for developing and releasing systems management software solutions for Dell's OpenManage product for servers.
- Products include cluster management, network management, peripheral management, remote manageability solutions, etc.
- Solutions provided are part of suite delivered with all servers and include integration of industry standard framework technologies such as HP OpenView NNM, ManageX, ClusterX by utilizing industry standard protocols such as SNMP, DMI, and CIM.
- Responsibilities included strategic architecture and design, development, managing development teams.

Device Driver and Kernel Senior engineer 06/1987 to 04/1998 NCR Corporation City, STATE

- Team Lead Windows NT Clustering Design/Development.
- Delivered software product called LifeKeeper, which provides NT clustering of servers, resources, and applications and that ensures high availability of through resource virtualization.
- Responsibilities included overall product architecture, component development, and technical project leadership and management.
- responsible for development of SCSI subsystem as part of the UNIX SVR4 MP-RAS.
- The OS was designed to run on SMP tightly coupled hardware architecture.
- My duties included full life-cycle development and product maintenance for SCSI target device drivers and host adapter drivers as part of the core operating system.
- Lead engineer in development of communications subsystem for high-end TP systems.
- Provided leadership in development protocol stacks operating over a SCSI link.
- High connectivity, high throughput, and high availability were met through developing on-board software and host resident software drivers
 and utilities.
- Provided the initial port of UNIX SVR4 to the NCR System 3000 line of computers--a tightly coupled SMP Intel based architecture.
- Duties included porting of various drivers, kernel components, and utilities, including portions of the original design of the SMP locking

strategy as well as multi-threading those portions of the kernel and drivers.

Education and Training

Undergraduate : Computer Science - Systems Computer Science & Mathematics 1987 California Polytechnic University; State University of New York City , State Computer Science - Systems Computer Science & Mathematics

Publications

The Multi-Threading of UNIX System V Release 4" Process Synchronization Method for Shell Scripting" Methodology for Disaster Recovery of Clusters" Method for Streamlining Customization of an Embedded Management System" Method for Sharing Data Store Across Event Management Frameworks" Method for Unification of Event Management Frameworks" Skills

C, C++, CIM, Clustering, COM, hardware, controller, Dell, Drivers, driving, Embedded Systems, engineer, XML, features, functional, futures, HP OpenView, Intel, Java, leadership, Team Lead, Linux, managing, access, MFC, Windows, NT, Windows NT, network management, object oriented, OO Design, Operating Systems, OS, operating system, Perl, product development, project leadership, protocols, quality, RAS, SCSI, servers, Shell, SMP, SNMP, Solaris, specification, strategy, strategic, system architecture, systems management, UML, UNIX, utilities, author